CHRISTIAN G. SOTO RAMIREZ

Front-End Web Developer

Indianapolis, IN | (812) 345-4861 | christam917@gmail.com | github.com/christdev22 | linkedin.com/in/christianramirezsoftwareengineer | Portfolio | linkedin.com/in/christianramirezsoftwareengineer | linkedin.com/in/christianramirezsoftwareengineer | linkedin.com/in/christianramirezsoftwareengineer | <a href="mailto:

SUMMARY

Recently graduated Front-End Developer with an intensive certification in front-end web development and advanced education in project management, information systems security, information technology, and software systems engineering. More than 5 years of experience in providing excellent customer service. Completed a project-based 6-mo certificate program in front-end web development, gaining skills in navigating and creating functions in the DOM, developing JavaScript Data Models, and Object-Oriented Programming.

EDUCATION

Associate Front-End Web Development Certificate

Kenzie Academy from Southern New Hampshire University

Graduation Date: July 2022

- Gained proficiency in using HTML, CSS, and JavaScript to build innovative web applications.
- Learned best coding practices to complete team-based projects in a deadline-driven environment.

Master of Science in Project Management with a concentration in Information Systems Security

Colorado Technical University

Graduation Date: August 2021

- Conducted sophisticated research security analysis on Linux (RHEL/CentOS) as Sysadmin for a project.
- Created resourceful Networking and Troubleshooting (TCP/IP, DNS, traceroute, and dig).
- Implemented intuitive Apache Hadoop ecosystem on gigabytes of data for a team-based project.

Bachelor of Science in Information Technology Specialization Software Systems Engineering

Colorado Technical University

Graduation Date: July 2020

- Built extensive relational database systems to configure TCP/IP, DNS, and DHCP protocols for firewalls.
- Developed versatile Java programs to calculate estimates on product cost and labor.
- Collaborated on programming a Java app for Big Data in quantitative and qualitative analysis.

SKILLS

Languages: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Git, Zoom, GitHub, Slack, Node, React, Google Docs, Microsoft Word, Python, Terminal, SQL, WordPress

Areas of Knowledge: Front-end Web Development, Data Structures, Troubleshooting, Website Design, Test Writing/ QA Testing, Debugging, Database / Information Management, Network Security

RELEVANT EXPERIENCE

ACME Website Template Project | Project Manager | Colorado Technical University

June 2018

- HTML | CSS | JavaScript | https://chrisdev22.github.io/ACME/
 - Independently designed and developed a website template from scratch over the course of 2 weeks to explore different types of frameworks and layouts.
 - Fully developed the front-end of a website by integrating different libraries from JavaScript and adding features, such as buttons, text boxes, and forms, to create an appealing website layout.
 - Administered ideal layout to enable user-friendly navigation across multiple pages in one single platform.

Crusaders Responsive Design Project | Team Lead | Colorado Technical University

Aug 2018

HTML | CSS | JavaScript | Bootstrap | Popper.js | Font Awesome | https://chrisdev22.github.io/Crusaders/

- Developed and designed a mock website by researching user needs for SaaS (Software as a Service) companies and consistently adapting design to be both creative and accessible.
- Led a team of 5 to create a new procedure by integrating an Apple API, which cut our beta testing phase by 12%, resulting in the prototype being finished weeks ahead of our competitors.
- Ranked 1st in creativity out of 4 teams after presenting to the class and was awarded 10 extra points.
- Increased data availability by implementing a Bootstrap framework for responsive design.
- Created buttons, flexboxes, and integrated an Apple API to add fun emojis to the website.

Lamp Text Editor Project | Project Manager | Kenzie Academy

HTML | CSS | JavaScript | https://chrisdev22.github.io/LampTE/

- Pioneered comprehensive text editor that identifies user input to perform text analysis.
- Streamlined research of input data to calculate the number of characters, words, and types of punctuation being used per user.

Fulfillment Associate Tier 1

April 2020 - Present

Greenwood, IN

June 2022

- Assistant problem-solver to fix shipment label boxes to sideline them for quality control.
- Improved productivity to 95% during peak season by real-time sortation.

Customer Service Representative

February 2019 - April 2020

Indianapolis, IN

Lowe's Home Improvement

- Addressed customer sales orders, processed refunds, and resolving customer complaints.
- Awarded Employee of the Month in May 2019 after receiving a 94% positive rating via customer surveys.
- Trained employees about the effectiveness of quality of engagement for excellent customer experience.

Customer Service Representative

June 2018 - February 2019

McDonald's

Amazon

Bloomington, IN

- Served to succeed in maintaining exceptional communication with customers at the restaurant.
- Trained new hires with approachable conversational etiquette to listen to customer requests efficiently.